Inventory of the Frank H. Higgins Papers, 1917-1959
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank H. Higgins Papers,
1917-1959
69007
Higgins, Frank Henry, 1890-1973
2 manuscript boxes, 13 scrapbooks, 2 envelopes. (6.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, photographs, printed matter, and memorabilia, relating to American defense policy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Army.; United States. Dept. of the Army.; Economic assistance, American.; World War, 1939-1945.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Military policy.
Abstract
Papers and materials (1917-1959) relating to the career of Frank H. Higgins especially pertaining to his appointments as an Army Colonel, as assistant to the Chief of Ordnance, War Dept., 1942-1945; Chief of the Machinery and Equipment Section, Marshall Plan, Paris, 1949-1950; Assistant Secretary of U. S. Army 1954-1959.
The materials were received from Mr. Frank H. Higgins, January 1969.
Container List
The first 12 volumes include correspondence, photographs, congratulatory letters, printed matter, personal memorabilia pertaining to Mr. Higgins' career as outlined above. (The dates are close approximations)
- Ap. 1917-June 1954 (Volume Vol. 1)
- Ag. 1954-Nov. 1954 (Volume Vol. 2)
- Oct. 1954-Dec. 1954 (Volume Vol. 3)
- Jan.-June 1955 (Volume Vol. 4)
- July-Dec. 1955 (Volume Vol. 5)
- Jan.-June 1956 (Volume Vol. 6)
- June-Dec. 1956 (Volume Vol. 7)
- Jan.-June 1957 (Volume Vol. 8)
- July-Dec. 1957 (Volume Vol. 9)
- 10 Jan-June 1958 (Volume Vol. 10)
- 11 July-Oct. 1958 (Volume Vol. 11)
- Nov. 1958-Mar. 1959 (Volume Vol. 12)
- Papers pertaining to Col. Higgins' work in the Machinery and Equipment section ECA 1949-1950., 1 notebook. (Box 1)
- "Cointra" - comercio industria y transportes, S.A. Puzol Valencia España 7-VI-1955., Photograph album.
- Visit of the San Francisco Ordnance district 4-5 Ag. 1955., Annotated, Illustrated booklet.
- Visit to Alco products, Inc. Feb. 8, 1956., Photograph album.
- Visit to Fort Shafter, Hawaii 14-18 Ap. 1956., Illustrated booklet.
- Visit to Rossford Ordnance Depot 28 Nov. 1956., Annotated, Illustrated booklet. (Box 2)
- Procurement conference. San Francisco, 9 Dec. 1957., Annotated photograph booklet with clippings.
- Northrop Aircraft, Inc. Radioplane division Anaheim division 11 Dec. 1957., Illustrated booklet.
- CHIHOA collecting point (Acres of diamonds) 1956, 1958., Illustrated booklet.
- Visit to Korea...2-5 July, 1958., Illustrated, annotated booklet.
- U. S. Army. Pacific Command. A memento illustrated booklet 16-18 July 1958 ...visit to Fort Shafter, Hawaii.
- Sons of the American Revolution. Phil., Feb. 21, 1959. Brochure of Washington Day Luncheon., Illustrated booklet.
- Album of appreciative letters pertaining to Mr. Frank H. Higgins' tenure of office as Assistant Secretary of the U.S. Army written at the time of his resignation in 1959. Letters include those from Pres. Eisenhower, Richard Nixon, and other important personages of the administration, armed services, and industry. Also included are programs, speeches, photographs, and memorabilia pertaining to the farewell ceremonies of Mr. Higgins. (Othertype On shelf with collection)
- Envelope of letters supplementing those in item 13 plus ephemeral memorabilia. (Box 2)
- Presidio of San Francisco Headquarters Sixth Army., Illustrated booklet.
- Headquarters Continental Army Command. Fort Monroe, Va., Illustrated booklet.